All right then gang, in this lesson, I want to talk about something called MCP and MCP servers, which can give Clarko the ability to connect and communicate with external data sources, services, and APIs.For example,When I'm working with Claude in this project right now, it knows about my project and it can use all its built-in tools to make changes and run bash commands and whatnot.But those tools only extend to the scope of this codebase, right?
好的，各位，在這一課中，我想討論一個叫做 MCP 和 MCP 伺服器的東西，它可以讓 Claude Code 具備連接和與外部資料來源、服務及 API 進行通訊的能力。例如，當我現在在這個專案中與 Claude 合作時，它了解我的專案，可以使用所有內建工具來進行修改、執行 Bash 指令等等。但這些工具只延伸到這個程式碼庫的範圍，對吧？
And there's no tools for Claude code to interact with external data sources, third-party services, or APIs.I can't tell it, for example, to reach out to a database to analyze my tables or even create a new one for me because it doesn't have the tools to do that, but that's where MCP servers come into play.So just very briefly, MCP stands for Model Context Protocol.It was designed by Anthropic, who made Claude Code, and it defines a way that AI models can interact with external sources.
Claude Code 沒有任何工具可以與外部資料來源、第三方服務或 API 互動。我不能告訴它，例如，連到一個資料庫來分析我的表格，甚至為我建立一個新的，因為它沒有那樣做的工具。但這就是 MCP 伺服器發揮作用的地方。簡單來說，MCP 代表模型上下文協議，由開發了 Claude Code 的 Anthropic 設計，它定義了一種 AI 模型與外部來源互動的方式。
And we do this by providing them with additional tools and context through MCP servers.And different MCP servers come with different tools to do different things and interact with different sources.So you can think of an MCP server as something you can essentially plug into Claude Code or whatever client you're using, and then ClaudeClaude, directed by the AI model, can use whatever tools the server provides to interact with some external data source.
我們透過 MCP 伺服器為它們提供額外的工具和上下文來做到這一點。不同的 MCP 伺服器附帶不同的工具，用於做不同的事情並與不同的來源互動。所以你可以把 MCP 伺服器想成是你可以基本上插入 Claude Code 或你正在使用的任何客戶端的東西，然後由 AI 模型指導的 Claude 就可以使用伺服器提供的任何工具來與某些外部資料來源互動。
For example, the Supabase MCP server contains tools to do things like list tables, deploy edge functions, and even execute SQL commands.So if I installed the Supabase MCP server, Claude would have access to all those tools, and I could say to Claude code,read the blogs table in Supabase, make an interface to model the records.And in response, Claude would check for any tools it can use to do this, and it would find one in this Supabase MCP server.
例如，Supabase MCP 伺服器包含了列出表格、部署 Edge Functions，甚至執行 SQL 指令等工具。所以如果我安裝了 Supabase MCP 伺服器，Claude 就可以存取所有那些工具，我可以對 Claude Code 說：「讀取 Supabase 中的 blogs 表格，建立一個介面來模型化那些記錄。」作為回應，Claude 會檢查它可以用來做這件事的任何工具，並在 Supabase MCP 伺服器中找到一個。
It would then use that tool, which is just a function defined within the server, to reach out to the database and find the blogs table.It would read it and then return the format of that table to Claude Code, and then using that data, Claude Code could decide how to make the interface.So when we use MCP servers, it's not the AI itself or the client like Claudecode that reaches out directly to these external sources.
然後它會使用那個工具（只是伺服器中定義的一個函數）來連接資料庫並找到 blogs 表格。它會讀取它，然後將那個表格的格式回傳給 Claude Code，然後使用那些資料，Claude Code 可以決定如何建立介面。所以當我們使用 MCP 伺服器時，不是 AI 本身或像 Claude Code 這樣的客戶端直接連接到這些外部來源。
It's the MCP server that does that, and then it provides Claude code or whatever client you might be using with the ability to call and use those tools.Another MCP server called Playwright provides AI models with the tools to open a browser, navigate through web pages, inspect elements, take screenshots.The Context7 MCP server provides tools to get up-to-date documentation from a lot of frameworks and libraries, which you can then ask Claude Code to use when implementing new features using those frameworks or libraries.
而是 MCP 伺服器做那件事，然後為 Claude Code 或你可能使用的任何客戶端提供呼叫和使用那些工具的能力。另一個叫做 Playwright 的 MCP 伺服器為 AI 模型提供了開啟瀏覽器、瀏覽網頁、檢查元素、截圖的工具。Context7 MCP 伺服器提供了從許多框架和函式庫獲取最新文件的工具，你可以請 Claude Code 在使用那些框架或函式庫實作新功能時使用這些文件。
And there's loads more too, which you can find on websites like this one, pulsemcp.com.So definitely check that out.We're going to install these two servers right here, Context7 and Playwright.And over the next couple of lessons, we're going to put them to use in our workflow.First though, how do we actually add the servers?Well, if we take a look at the Claude code docs on the MCP installation section, you can see that we can add them locally on our computer or by connecting to them remotely.
還有很多其他的，你可以在像 pulsemcp.com 這樣的網站上找到，一定要去看看。我們要安裝這裡這兩個伺服器：Context7 和 Playwright。在接下來的幾課中，我們要在工作流程中使用它們。不過首先，我們實際上如何新增這些伺服器呢？如果我們查看 Claude Code 文件中的 MCP 安裝部分，你可以看到我們可以在本機電腦上新增它們，或通過遠端連接它們。
Now, we'll be adding the servers locally, so we'll be using this option at the top.And the way we do this is by using the command Claude MCP add and then whatever the server name is, then the command and any arguments.Also, if you're on Windows, then you're currently, you'll need to add one more thing, which if we scroll down here, you're going to see it in a big yellow warning box, and that is to
我們將在本機新增伺服器，所以我們將使用頂部的這個選項。我們這樣做的方式是使用指令 claude mcp add，然後是伺服器名稱，接著是指令和任何參數。另外，如果你在 Windows 上，你目前需要再新增一件事，如果我們往下捲動，你會在一個大的黃色警告框中看到它，那就是要新增
To add cmd and then forward slash c, so the cmd part opens the Windows command line to run the command, the forward slash c part makes sure the shell gets closed after it's been run.Now, normally, when we use an MCP server, the server docs gives us the whole string to copy and paste in a terminal, which is then going to add the server.But just be aware that you might need to add the cmd forward slash CPAR if you're on Windows for servers that use NPX.Otherwise, it might not work correctly.
cmd 然後斜線 c，所以 cmd 部分開啟 Windows 命令列來執行指令，斜線 c 部分確保在執行完後 shell 會被關閉。通常，當我們使用 MCP 伺服器時，伺服器文件給了我們一整段字串可以複製貼上到終端機中，這樣就會新增伺服器。但請注意，對於使用 npx 的伺服器，如果你在 Windows 上，你可能需要新增 cmd /c 的部分，否則可能無法正確運作。
Anyway, let's head back to the Context 7 MCP page.And we're going to see what it says there about the installation.So if we click on this MCP link up at the top, it should take us to the GitHub page for the server, which it does.And then if you scroll right down, we should eventually see a bunch of options for adding the server to different clients.One of those options should be Claude code.So click on that to expand it, and we're going to get a few different options.The first two are for remote server connections.
無論如何，讓我們回到 Context7 MCP 頁面，看看它對安裝說了什麼。如果我們點擊頂部的這個 MCP 連結，它應該帶我們到伺服器的 GitHub 頁面，確實是的。然後如果你一路捲動到底部，我們最終應該會看到一堆將伺服器新增到不同客戶端的選項，其中一個選項應該是 Claude Code。點擊它展開，我們會獲得幾個不同的選項，前兩個是遠端伺服器連線。
The one at the bottom is for a local connection.So we say Claude MCP add, then the server name, which is context 7, then we have this double dash, then the npx command.So we're going to copy this now and paste it into the terminal, and then we're also going to make a few edits.So then I've pasted this into my terminal already, and I'm just going to add another few things in.The first thing we'll do is we're going to add another flag to this, just before the double dash, and that is the scope flag.
底部的那個是用於本地連線。我們說 claude mcp add，然後是伺服器名稱 context7，接著是雙破折號，再是 npx 指令。我們現在要複製它並貼入終端機，然後我們還要做一些編輯。我已經將它貼入我的終端機了，我只是要再新增幾件事。我們要做的第一件事是在雙破折號之前新增另一個旗標，那就是 scope 旗標。
So when we add MCP servers with Claude code, we can add them to three different scopes.Project scope, where the MCP setup gets pushed to remote and everyone working on the project can use the MCPs added to the project.Local scope, which is where only you can use the MCP server on this particular project, and global scope, which is when the MCPsis added globally to Claude code and you can use it for any project on your computer.
所以當我們使用 Claude Code 新增 MCP 伺服器時，我們可以將它們新增到三種不同的範圍。專案範圍，MCP 設定會推送到遠端，所有在專案上工作的人都可以使用新增到專案中的 MCP；本地範圍，只有你能在這個特定專案上使用 MCP 伺服器；以及全域範圍，MCP 被全域新增到 Claude Code，你可以在電腦上的任何專案中使用它。
Now the default scope is local, but I want to make it a project scope so that we can see the MCP configuration here in the project directory.And mostly I use either project or global scope.I very rarely use local scope.Anyway, to add this scope, we use the scope flag followed by project to specify project scope.And again, this could also be local or global.
預設範圍是本地，但我想讓它成為專案範圍，這樣我們就可以在專案目錄中看到 MCP 配置。我通常使用專案或全域範圍，很少使用本地範圍。無論如何，要新增這個範圍，我們使用 scope 旗標後跟 project 來指定專案範圍，同樣這也可以是 local 或 global。
Now before we go any further, I will say this, if you're running Claude code natively on Windows, it can be a little bit buggy when you're adding MCP servers, at least at the time of recording this video.If you're on a Mac, then you probably won't have to jump through any hoops or workarounds and you can just hit enter right now and this would work.If you're on Windows though, you have to do a few more things for it to work properly.
在我們繼續之前，我要說這個：如果你在 Windows 上原生執行 Claude Code，在新增 MCP 伺服器時可能會有一些問題，至少在錄製這部影片時是這樣。如果你在 Mac 上，你可能不需要做任何繞道或變通方法，你現在就可以按 Enter，這樣就會運作。但如果你在 Windows 上，你需要多做幾件事才能讓它正常工作。
First, we have to add the cmd and then forward slash cbit just before the rest of this npx command like we talked about earlier.Secondly, if weWe run this right now, we're going to get an error, which I'll show you by hitting enter, and that error says there's an unknown option Y, which comes right after the npx bit.Now, the Y flag is for auto-accepting defaults to prompts when some package is installed, and it needs to be there in this case.So, how do we get around this?
首先，我們必須在其餘 npx 指令之前加上 cmd 然後斜線 c，就像我們之前討論的那樣。其次，如果我們現在執行這個，我們會得到一個錯誤，我會按 Enter 來向你展示，那個錯誤說有一個未知的 -y 選項，它出現在 npx 部分之後。現在，-y 旗標是用於在安裝某些套件時自動接受預設提示，在這種情況下它需要在那裡。那麼，我們如何解決這個問題？
Well, one solution is to run the whole thing without the Y flag first, which we'll do now.And when we do that, it's gonna work, and Claude code makes this .mcp.json file in the root of the project.Now, if we take a look at that, we'll see this JSON object with an MCP service property inside, and it's within this property that all project level servers get added.So we can see this context seven one right here that we just added, and inside that, the server's configured with these different properties.
好吧，一個解決方案是先不帶 -y 旗標執行整個命令，這是我們現在要做的。當我們這樣做時，它會運作，Claude Code 在專案根目錄中建立這個 .mcp.json 檔案。如果我們看一下那個，我們會看到這個 JSON 物件，裡面有一個 MCP service 屬性，所有專案層級的伺服器都在這個屬性中被新增。所以我們可以在這裡看到我們剛才新增的 context7 那個，在它裡面，伺服器用這些不同的屬性進行配置。
The type is standard in out since this is a local MCP connection that we added.The command is CMD and that's because on Windows we added that extra CMD part.Then we have some arguments including the forward slash C bit, which we also added because we're on Windows.Now again, if you're on a Mac, this will probably look a little bit different and you won't need to make any changes.But on Windows, because we removed that hyphen Y flag, we should now manually add this in to the arguments array after the NPX one.So let's do that
type 是 standard in out，因為這是我們新增的本地 MCP 連線。command 是 cmd，那是因為在 Windows 上我們新增了那個額外的 cmd 部分。然後我們有一些參數，包括斜線 c 的部分，我們也新增了它，因為我們在 Windows 上。再次說明，如果你在 Mac 上，這可能看起來有些不同，你不需要做任何更改。但在 Windows 上，因為我們移除了 -y 旗標，現在我們應該手動在 npx 那個後面的 arguments 陣列中新增它。讓我們現在這樣做
now and then save the file.
然後儲存檔案。
Right then, so hopefully now that's all going to work when we start up Claude Code, but I do think this whole workaround when using Windows is a little bit clunky and I'm hoping that it's something that can be made simpler in the future and maybe when you're watching this video it will be.Anyway, now let's try using this.Now, when I've just tried using this MCP server, I got some kind of connection error.It failed.It didn't work for whatever reason.So I'm actually going to use the remote server from context 7.
好的，希望現在當我們啟動 Claude Code 時，這一切都能正常工作，但我確實認為在 Windows 上使用時這整個變通方法有點笨拙，我希望未來可以讓它變得更簡單，也許當你看這部影片時它已經改進了。無論如何，現在讓我們試著使用這個。我剛才試著使用這個 MCP 伺服器，得到了某種連線錯誤，它失敗了，不知為何無法運作。所以我實際上要改用 Context7 的遠端伺服器。
It's strange because when I tried this out before recording, it did work.Everything was fine.But this is the problem sometimes because Claude code is new, MCP servers are new, they're changing a lot.Sometimes things can just not work and it might take a little while for things to level out.So what I'm going to do now is go back to the docs and look for the other command I needrun for a remote server.So we're going to go ahead with this one right here which uses HTTP as the transport system.So let's copy this.
這很奇怪，因為在錄製前我試過時是可以運作的，一切都很正常。但有時候就是這樣，因為 Claude Code 是新的，MCP 伺服器也是新的，它們在快速改變，有時候事情就是無法運作，可能需要一些時間才能穩定下來。所以我現在要做的是回到文件，查找遠端伺服器需要執行的另一個指令。我們將使用這裡這個，它使用 HTTP 作為傳輸系統，讓我們複製這個。
Alright so I've pasted that into my terminal but I'm going to add one more thing and that is the scope flag after the server name.So after context 7 do double dash then scope and then project to add this at a project level.Press enter.Hopefully now it's going to add that server for us and if we close this terminal and take a look over here we should see the mcp.json file and yet we see that contextseven property inside.
好的，我已經把它貼入我的終端機了，但我要再新增一件事，那就是在伺服器名稱後面加上 scope 旗標。所以在 context7 後面加上雙破折號，然後是 scope，再是 project，以在專案層級新增這個。按 Enter，希望現在它會為我們新增那個伺服器，如果我們關閉這個終端機並在這裡查看，應該就能看到 mcp.json 檔案，確實，我們在裡面看到了 context7 那個屬性。
This time the type is HTTP because we're using a remote connection and this is the URL for the server as well.Cool.So now we need to start Claude backup, which I'm going to do over here by tapping Claude and then press enter.Let's get rid of the file tree.And then inside here I'm going to say forward slash MCP and this time hopefully we will see the context seven.Okay, it failed to connect.What I'm going to do is press enter andAnd then I'm going to reconnect to this to see if it does connect this time.
這次 type 是 HTTP，因為我們使用遠端連線，這也是伺服器的 URL，很好。所以現在我們需要重新啟動 Claude，我要在這裡輸入 claude 然後按 Enter 來啟動它。讓我們關掉檔案樹，然後在這裡我要輸入 /mcp，希望這次我們可以看到 context7。好的，它連線失敗了，我要按 Enter，然後我要重新連線，看看這次是否能連上。
Okay, looks like it's worked.So forward slash MCP.Now we can see a green tick next to that.We're connected to context 7 and we can start using it.So let me escape out of that.Okay, so now I'm going to get Claude Co to use Context Seven by typing in this prompt, and it says, Can you check the latest Tailwind docs to see if the theme variables are correctly configured in the global CSS file?Use Context Seven.I'm also going to reference that CSS file so it knows where to look, so that's source app and then globals.
好的，看起來它成功了。輸入 /mcp，現在我們可以看到旁邊有一個綠色勾號，我們已連接到 Context7，可以開始使用它了。讓我按 Escape 退出。好的，現在我要輸入這個提示詞讓 Claude Code 使用 Context7：「你能檢查最新的 Tailwind 文件，看看主題變數是否在全域 CSS 檔案中正確配置嗎？請使用 Context7。」我也要參考那個 CSS 檔案，讓它知道要在哪裡查看，輸入 src/app 然後是 globals。
dot CSS.And then I'm going to press enter.But before I do that, notice I said use context seven.That's so it explicitly knows to use that MCP server to get the up-to-date information.So let me press enter to do this.And now it wants to use this resolve library ID tool from context seven.And then it wants to use an additional tool and it wants my permission to do this.So I'm going to press yes right here.
.css，然後按 Enter。但在我這樣做之前，注意我說了「使用 Context7」，這樣它就明確知道要使用那個 MCP 伺服器來獲取最新資訊。讓我按 Enter 來執行這個。現在它想使用 Context7 的 resolve library ID 工具，然後它想使用一個額外的工具，並需要我的許可。所以我要在這裡按是。
And now you can see right here, it says, looking at your Tailwind CSS configuration, your theme variables are correctly configured, blah, blah, blah.It's properly structured.Okay, so everything is as it should be.Awesome.So one thing I like to do with Context 7 is tell Claude Code to use it whenever it needs to implement some feature using a third-party framework or library because a lot of the time it can use legacy code.
現在你可以看到在這裡，它說：「查看你的 Tailwind CSS 配置，你的主題變數配置正確，blah blah blah，結構正確。」好的，所以一切都符合預期，太棒了。我喜歡使用 Context7 的一件事是告訴 Claude Code，每當需要使用第三方框架或函式庫來實作某些功能時就使用它，因為很多時候它可能會使用舊版程式碼。
So I want to make sure that it uses the up-to-date documentation every time that it creates some code using those frameworks.And that's not just Claude Code, by the way, that's any AI tool or model.They can all use legacy code because they're trained on that legacy code.So what I'm going to do is add a memory using the hash over here.So I've
所以我想確保它在使用那些框架建立某些程式碼時，每次都使用最新的文件。而且不只是 Claude Code，任何 AI 工具或模型都是如此，它們都可能使用舊版程式碼，因為它們是在那些舊版程式碼上訓練的。所以我要在這裡使用井字號新增一個記憶，我已經
Press hash, we're going to add a memory, and then I'm going to paste in this memory that says, Use context 7 to check up-to-date docs when needed for implementing new libraries or frameworks or adding features using them.So, if I press enter, we're going to add that to the project memory, and if we then open this file up, we should see that at the bottom now.Yep, there it is.Awesome.
按了井字號，我們要新增一個記憶，然後我要貼入這個記憶，它說：「在需要時使用 Context7 來查看實作新函式庫或框架，或使用它們新增功能時的最新文件。」如果我按 Enter，我們要將其新增到專案記憶，如果我們打開這個檔案，應該就能在底部看到它了，是的，就在那裡，太棒了。
Okay then, so now we're going to add another server called Playwright, which provides Claude code with the tools to do things like open a browser, click on links, take screenshots, etc.So I'm on the Playwright MCP page right here, and for Claude code it says run this command, which because we're on Windows, we're going to have to tweak again.I also want to make sure we're using project scope when we add it.So copy this command, then head back to your terminal.
好的，現在我們要新增另一個叫做 Playwright 的伺服器，它為 Claude Code 提供了開啟瀏覽器、點擊連結、截圖等工具。我現在在 Playwright MCP 頁面，對於 Claude Code 它說執行這個指令，但因為我們在 Windows 上，我們需要再次調整它。我也想確保我們在新增它時使用專案範圍。複製這個指令，然後回到你的終端機。
So then I've already added this command in, as well as two other things, the scope flag first of all over here.to say we want to add this at project level and then also the CMD forward slash C part because we're running this on Windows.This time we don't need to add the Y flag for this particular server.Alright so now let's hit enter.Hopefully that's going to add the playwright server to the mcp.json file.
好的，我已經輸入了這個指令，以及另外兩件事：首先是這裡的 scope 旗標，用來指定我們想在專案層級新增這個；然後是 cmd /c 的部分，因為我們在 Windows 上執行這個。這次我們不需要為這個特定伺服器新增 -y 旗標。好的，現在讓我們按 Enter，希望這會將 Playwright 伺服器新增到 mcp.json 檔案。
So let's take a look at that over here and yet we can see we've got the context 7 one now and also the playwright one and this time the type is standard in out the command CMD then the argumentsdown here.Awesome.So then, now we need to start Claude back up again so that we can try using this.Okay, so I've started Claude up and the first thing I'm going to do is use the MCP tool to make sure that they're connected correctly.Yep, okay, cool.
讓我們在這裡看看，是的，我們可以看到我們現在有 context7 那個，還有 playwright 那個，這次 type 是 standard in out，command 是 cmd，然後是這裡的 arguments，太棒了。好的，現在我們需要再次啟動 Claude，這樣我們就可以試著使用它了。好的，我已經啟動了 Claude，我要做的第一件事是使用 /mcp 工具確保它們連線正確。是的，好的，很好。
And now I'm going to escape and I'm just going to ask Claude code to maybe open a browser and navigate to netninja.dev and give me a summaryof the site.So this is just to show you that it can navigate to a site using Playwright or Playwright can on its behalf and provide feedback that we need.So it's going to ask for permission, first of all.So we'll say yes.
現在我要按 Escape，然後我只是要請 Claude Code 開啟一個瀏覽器，瀏覽到 netninja.dev，並給我一個網站的摘要。這只是為了向你展示它可以使用 Playwright 瀏覽到一個網站，或者 Playwright 可以代表它這樣做，並提供我們需要的回饋。所以它首先要請求許可，我們就說是。
And then on my other screen, it's opened up netninja.dev, which we can see right here.So it's just going to do its browsing.I'm going to take that back off screen.
然後在我的另一個螢幕上，它開啟了 netninja.dev，我們可以在這裡看到。所以它就要進行瀏覽了，我要把它移到螢幕外。
All right, so now it's come back with a little bit of information.It says NetNinja is a comprehensive coding education platform created by Sean, focused on web development training.The site positions itself as a coding dojo where aspiring developers become coding ninjas.So I'm quite pleased with that.It gives us this other information about it as well, which is quite extensive, to be honest.But Playwright can do more than just this.And what I'd like to do is use Playwright to give us feedback on the UX of components that we
好的，現在它回來了，帶來了一些資訊。它說：「NetNinja 是一個由 Shaun 建立的綜合性編程教育平台，專注於網頁開發培訓。這個網站將自己定位為一個編程道場，有抱負的開發者在這裡成為編程忍者。」我對此相當滿意，它也提供了其他相當詳盡的資訊，老實說。但 Playwright 能做的不止這些，我想做的是使用 Playwright 對我們
make when it's used them in the browser.So in the next lesson, what we're going to be doing is making our own sub-agent with Claude code, and we're going to be using the Playwright MCP from within that sub-agent to do just that.
製作的元件在瀏覽器中使用時提供 UX 回饋。所以在下一課，我們要做的是使用 Claude Code 製作我們自己的子代理，我們將在那個子代理中使用 Playwright MCP 來做到這一點。